Everyone bases their Game of the Year videos on shit like gameplay.
They never ask the important stuff, like, for example:
Is the game more fun than driving a forklift?
No.
They never are, forklifts win every time.
Before I unveil the top 2, let's roast all the other games.
I have played every game that came out this year,
But Stardew Valley is the only one I can remember.
Not because it was the most memorable game,
because it was first.
And if you're not first, you are last.
But, I can't award it because the creator did an update with a bunch of free content.
So I don't know if it's good anymore.
Another game that's got an update is No Man's Sky.
They released a base building update.
When people compared it to an Early Access game, they were joking.
They didn't mean 'go for it'.
I could give this game the award...
but the chances of that are incredibly rare.
Not my biggest dissapointment of the year.
That award goes to Mankind Divided.
After the events of the last game, Jenson has become an alcoholic,
and therefore had to move to Prague.
Gameplay is super polished, so why fail on the story?
I have a feeling it's because so many people complained about Augmental Pre-order.
The ending is extremely abrupt.
You are playing and-
I've spent 7 hours to come up with something wicked to say about Gears of War 4,
and so far I have nothing.
And maybe that sums up the game.
I did not think the series would survive this long,
and apparently, it's good.
But, Microsoft...
Maybe it's time to take Gears of War out of the barn.
If Game of the Year was based on scale, not quality,
Pokémon GO would exterminate the competition.
Never got to play it.
And that being accessed by 5 billion people,
it's going to be down.
A lot.
For us YouTube people, it was great.
You throw together a video in an hour and get like, 300 000 views.
I would never do that, though.
Because I have morals.
But you don't have to capture Pokémon in a sad, abandoned industrial zone,
you can travel to Aloha!
Welcome to Pokémon Sun,
where classic Pokémon have been mutated because of nuclear testing.
The new Pokémon game is in Hawaii.
For God's sake, GameFreak,
you are missing your chance to put a game in North Korea.
Imagine the game starting with your family being executed.
The North Korean Pokémon could look like regular Pokémon,
except thinner.
We'll call it
Pokémon: Star and Missile.
In the Final Fantasy series, we have played as the Chosen One and knights for six games,
then terrorists,
high school students,
one athlete,
and the brick wall.
Now finally, we get to play as a boy band.
The game takes place in 1995, and then this purple-haired guy
steals the royal Pogs collection.
That might not have been the story,
but I don't speak Japanese, so what do you want from me?
I think XV might be the the first Final Fantasy game
to take place in Current Day or near future.
Therefore, it's false marketing.
Because then it's not Final Fantasy.
It's Final Contemporary.
On topic of Japan,
development of The Last Guardian was started by the League of Nations.
Now, 100 years later, it's out.
And it's all right.
It was going to be released back in 2011,
Maybe it would've had a better chance competing with games like
Dark Souls,
Uncharted,
Deus Ex,
Battlefiel-...
Wait.
You play as a little boy and you have a bird-dog named Trico.
Sounds Latin-American
Is that why you have a hard time communicating because the kid can't speak Spanish?
The animation is beautiful.
This is why I fucking hate video games, they have to ruin everything with gameplay.
Strategy games!
XCOM has an 88% on Metacritic,
so this is clearly a miss.
Not so fun when it happens to you, Firaxis.
Firaxis also made Civilization VI,
a game I can't play yet.
Because I don't know how, as they've removed advisors.
They changed the graphics style to cute and cartoony,
so they had to replace Denmark with Norway.
But why no Venice?
He's been a staple of the Civilization franchise ever since,
eh,
The last expansion!
The AI is as dumb as a rock.
So, all in all, Civilization VI is going to be fantastic.
In a couple of years.
5$ for a new civilization!
Fuck off!
While we're talking about DLC,
Total War: Warhammer is the game that I have played the most this year.
It's not my favorite Game of the Year,
just my slowest.
But it can't win because, it's a pretty
obvious ripoff of Warcraft.